Miguel Enriquez

DevOps/SRE + Microservices Specialist

SUMMARY

Specialist building Digital Platforms using Microservices & Evolutionary architectures, implementing cross-cutting concerns such as observability, security, CI/CD. Focused on DevOps and SRE practices. Partnered with all kinds of companies: from Fortune 10 to small startups by guiding and building software platforms and services with a focus on product development.

EXPERIENCE

Indebted - Melbourne, Australia — Software Engineer

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

I worked integrating client systems to Indebted's platform using an event-based architecture.

 Worked on systems integration with clients to automate referrals from companies, bringing new business in a turmoiled market

Greyshore Associates - Charlotte, NC — Principal Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2021 - APRIL 2022

I work with companies during their transition to cloud-based services after the COVID-19 pandemic by building digital platforms and helping application developers to take their services to the cloud

- Boosted productivity of 4 workstreams by building a microservice platform and saved hours
 of development to 15 engineers in 3 different products by reducing time to market from
 months to days in large-scale operations.
- Facilitated multi-region infrastructure and CI/CD capabilities allowing new business from different regions (Europe, Japan, US). This translated into multiple revenue streams valued in millions of dollars.
- Consulted on a consolidated transporting company to build their IoT platform for vehicle tracking and material delivery.

ThoughtWorks - Dallas, TX — Senior Consultant

NOVEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2021

I delivered platforms that allow innovation, R&D to happen fast while maintaining developer experience as a focus to accelerate adoption. Recently, I have worked with Fortune 10 companies developing Digital Platforms creating reference architecture services, and designing CI/CD pipelines for such applications.

- Built a platform for dozens of microservices allowing hundreds of thousands of operations
 per second with high resilience allowing business opportunities to be boarded in weeks
 instead of months.
- Created complete code generation and delivery mechanisms facilitating business opportunities which reflected in faster time to market of new products.
- Mentored and trained consultants, client developers, and architects on microservices and evolutionary architectures. This increased the quality of shipped features and products allowing low-churn and high quality products.

Softtek - Dallas, TX —Site Reliability Engineer

FEBRUARY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

I worked in the airline industry maintaining and improving a critical application for aircraft/airport operations. Under strict guidelines, SLAs, and time constraints, I improved different aspects of the applications I maintained by correcting errors, improving the architecture, adding monitoring capabilities and detecting problems early.

• Brought observability and alerting best practices to established products reducing costs and downtime which reflected in better customer service, savings on maintenance.

Accenture - Austin/Dallas, TX —Front-End Engineer NOVEMBER 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016

Softtek - Mexico - Tech Lead APRIL 2013 - NOVEMBER 2014

mail: sftwr.mael@gmail.com

website: eldermael.io social media: @eldermael linkedin: eldermael

SKILLS & TECH

Cloud Architecture (AWS, Azure, 6 years), Kubernetes (AKS, EKS, K3s, Openshift, 6 years), Infrastructure (Terraform, Pulumi, SaltStack, Packer, 6 years), Microservices (Domain Driven Design, Platform Engineering, Fitness Functions, 8 years), CI/CD (Jenkins, Azure DevOps, 8 years)
Observability (Grafana, Prometheus, Thanos, 4 years), Scripting & Automation (Bash, Powershell, CLIs, 8 years), Frontend (React, D3.js, 2 years), Backend (Java 10 years, JavaScript 8 years, Spring Boot 6 years, Node 3 years, Golang 6 months).

PROJECTS

PirateDevRadio — Podcast (in Spanish)

Software development podcast aimed to generalist and discuss news in the software development world. I also produce a <u>newsletter</u>.

Talks, Panels, & Community Building

I give frequent talks about Microservices, DevOps, Java and other topics. Most can be found here.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree, Computer Systems Engineering. Zacatecas Institute of Technology 2005–2009